Software Engineer

Motivated and driven Software Engineer combining a blend of front-end and back-end experience to engineer modern full-stack applications with time and cost-saving solutions. More than five years of Software experience developing personal apps/projects and one year working in the startup industry. Skilled problem solver and fast learner who is eager to learn cutting edge technology and excited to be a prospect in the industry and implement acquired skills included below:

- Agile Methodology
- AWS
- Databases
- Algorithms

- Problem Solving
- Open-Source Frameworks
- Leadership
- MVC/MVT

Software Languages:

Python, Java, Node, JavaScript, Django, SQL, NOSQL, HTML, CSS, React, React-Native

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bazar Marketplace (Startup), Remote

February 2022 - August, 2022

Full-Stack Engineer (Contractor)

Tasked to build the Web version of the startup marketplace using Django framework to develop Backend-APIs catered for both the Web and Mobile apps, as well as architecting the Front-End of the Web-app using Django Templating/CSS, and assisted with the developing of Mobile-app using React-Native.

- Deployed a fully functional web app with over 5,000 visitors, that integrated all aspects of a functional marketplace such as browsing over 100,000 products/vendors, implementing stripe payments, and maintaining user Carts.
- Received "Exceptional" performance rating due to outstanding work on the web application portion of the marketplace that was completed on the agreed upon time of 6 months.
- Developed APIs to fetch over 1,000,000 data from the database stored in the AWS cloud
- Effectively used MVT pattern to create Django models/views necessary resulting in giving users visuals of the marketplace content
- Developed jQuery components and incorporated them with API requests allowing users to search for vendors/products, see randomized/popular products on the home page for every refresh, use Stripe to complete their payments, and maintain their carts.
- Gave the Web App a modern app look using CSS and Django Templating

- Maintained high standards in the agile ceremonies, ensuring attendance at daily Stand Ups and Scrums as well as the Sprint Planning/Reviews.
- Willingly took on additional projects to assist the React-Native team to develop APIs using
 Django REST framework for the mobile app which allowed users and merchants to create and
 maintain profiles.

ADDITIONAL RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Holy Transfiguration Monastery, Volunteer

January 2020-February 2020

 Helped a local church business by analyzing over 100,000 past sales data with regression models which determined the church was overpaying for shipping costs. The data was used to estimate the best possible shipping methods for future orders which saved them over \$20,000 in shipping costs to date.

Personal Projects

- Bible App
 - Personal Bible app that allows users to navigate the KJV Bible
 - Allows bookmarks, notes, highlights, and sharing of verses in the Bible
 - Allowed users to maintain profiles
 - o Implemented with React-Native and React-Native-Firebase

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

B.A. in Computer Science- Bridgewater State University, Boston, 2019-2023

AWS Cloud Practitioner Certificate- 2022